<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.04116</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1780 November 06</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>0 pages</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1780 November 06</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17801106</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>Hussey and Cumberland are in Spain. June conferred with Floridablanca on
            June 2 and was told of the Cumberland mission. Spain could not compromise her good faith
            with the United States. Floridablanca accepted some new bills from Jay. Floridablanca
            told Carmichael that the only difficulty on the treaty was the navigation of the
            Mississippi. Cumberland arrived June 19 but his business is not openly known. Jay's next
            conference with Floridablanca was on July 5: the loss of Charleston and death of
            Miralles discussed. The bills also discussed. Everything postponed at this conference.
            Jay then wrote several notes on the bills, but no answer from Floridablanca who avoided
            Jay on the excuse of illness. Jay then had a conference with Montmorin who said he would
            speak to Floridablanca in Jay's behalf. Jay's next meeting with Montmorin was less
            cordial and he told Jay nothing of the letter he had received from America. Montmorin
            was not able to discuss the American business with Floridablanca and suggested to Jay
            that he write another letter requesting an audience. Jay said he had come to submit
            propositions, not supplications, and if no more headway was made on the treaty soon he
            would return to America. Montmorin asked Jay if America was satisfied with the conduct
            of France and Jay said as far as he knew but was not sure France had interceded with
            Spain in America's favor. Montmorin indicated he could not interfere unless to mediate a
            specific point. Jay finally consented to ask for a conference. Montmorin would not admit
            whether Gardoqui was in town. Jay met with Gardoqui and stated the American position on
            the Mississippi, loans, and timber. Jay stressed the western desire for the Mississippi
            at the next meeting and Gardoqui said only future generations would need it and they
            could settle the question for themselves. Gardoqui stressed that America should have
            asked France for aid, not Spain who could ill afford to give it. Jay replied that
            America should have been told this in the beginning. Gardoqui authorized Jay to accept
            the bills coming due however. Jay suspected that France had brought Spain into the war
            by supporting her claim to exclusive control of the Mississippi. Spain said accept no
            more bills. Jay asked Congress to suspend drawing on him further. Conference with
            Floridablanca, Sept. 23: Floridablanca said he was sorry Spain could accept no more
            bills, and Jay said he should have told him that in the beginning since America wanted a
            loan, not a donation. Jay said the French treaties should be made the basis of one with
            Spain. Floridablanca said Spain and France had different interests. Jay said he hoped
            they could form a treaty on the basis of the points agreed upon and negotiate the
            others. Spain wants to be the balance in the whole struggle. She could have paid our
            loan if she had wanted to. No nation, especially absolute monarchies, has a
            disinterested regard for us. We should be independent of all nations. No answer from
            Vergennes to my letter. Vergennes told Montmorin he doubted whether France could
            help.</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh"
                 valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh"
                 valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79088877">
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">DNA</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">National Archives and Records Administration</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/item?mode=item&amp;key=columbia.jay.04116</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.04116_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>
