<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.03574</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Washington, George, 1732-1799</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1779 August 15</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>9</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1779 August 15</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17790815</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>In the report General Sullivan submitted to Congress there have been a
            number of misstatements. In providing for his own justification in case of misfortune,
            Sullivan is leaving Washington in a rather embarrassing position. The enclosed papers
            will provide background on Sullivan's preference for action along the Mohawk River and
            Washington's choice for another route. Nevertheless, the motives for the undertaking
            were to rescue the frontier from repeated attacks, and to answer the clamor of the areas
            and states concerned as well as the will of Congress. Extensive preparations were made
            for the offensive. To leave the frontier to the enemy when there is a chance of securing
            it would be, in Washington's opinion, a grave mistake. In hand of Richard Kidder Meade.
            Enclosures: 19 November 1778, Washington to Wadsworth; 18 December 1778, Washington to
            Philip Schuyler; 18 January 1779, Washington to Philip Schuyler; 25 January 1779,
            Washington to Philip Schuyler; 4 February 1779, Philip Schuyler to Washington; 7
            February 1779, Washington to Hand; 11 February 1779, Washington to Philip Schuyler;
            [after 7 February 1779, Hand to Washington? or after 11 February 1779, Philip Schuyler
            to Washington?]; 14 February 1779, Washington to Wadsworth; 24 February 1779, Washington
            to Greene; 26 February 1779, Washington to Philip Schuyler; 1 March 1779, Philip
            Schuyler to Washington; 2 March 1779, Washington to Flint; 3 March 1779, Washington to
            Reed; 4 March 1779, Washington to George Clinton; 6 March 1779, Washington to Sullivan;
            16 March 1779, Washington to Hand; 21 March 1779, Washington to Hane; 21 March 1779,
            Washington to Schuyler; 24 March 1779, Washington to Hand; 27 March 1779, Cuyler to
            Schuyler; 3 April 1779, Schuyler to Washington; 15 April 1779, Schuyler to Washington;
            16 April 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 18 April 1779, Chalonier and White to Flint; 19
            April 1779, Washington to James Clinton; 19 April 1779, Washington to Reed; 19 April
            1779, Washington to Schuyler; 20 April 1779, Washington to Wadsworth; 24 April 1779,
            Flint to Washington; 27 April 1779, Washington to Reed; 30 April 1779, Flint to
            Washington; 3 May 1779, Washington to George Clinton; 4 May 1779, Washington to
            Sullivan; 12 May 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 13 May 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 18
            May 1779, Council of Pennsylvania to Washington; 19 May 1779, Clayborne to Hand; 19 May
            1779, Washington to Sullivan; 20 May 1779, Washington to the Council of Pennsylvania; 21
            May 1779, Schuyler to Washington; 21 May 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 22 May 1779, Van
            Schaick to James Clinton; 23 May 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 23 May 1779, Washington
            to the Board of War; 24 May 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 24 May 1779, Washington to
            Sullivan; 24 May 1779, Blaine to Sullivan; 24 May 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 26 May
            1779, Sullivan to Washington; 28 May 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 28 May 1779, James
            Clinton to Washington; 31 May 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 31 May 1779, Washington to
            Sullivan; 31 May 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 1 June 1779, Blaine to Wadsworth; 2 June
            1779, Sullivan to Washington; 4 June 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 9 June 1779,
            Washington to Sullivan; 10 June 1779, "A friend in Canada in a Tory stile" to Schuyler;
            10 June 1779, Washington to James Clinton; 12 June 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 19 June
            1779, James Clinton to Washington; 21 June 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 25 June 1779,
            Sullivan to Washington; 26 June 1779, James Clinton to Washington; 27 June 1779,
            Washington to James Clinton; 27 June 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 28 June 1779,
            Washington to [George Clinton]; 29 June 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 30 June 1779,
            Schuyler to Washington; 30 June 1779, James Clinton to Washington; 1 July 1779,
            Washington to Sullivan; 3 July 1779, Wadsworth to Washington; 5 July 1779, Washington to
            Reed; 5 July 1779, Washington to Sullivan; [after 5 July 1779] Sullivan to Washington; 7
            July 1779, Schuyler to Washington; 14 July 1779, Sullivan to Washington; 23 July 1779,
            Washington to Schuyler; 29 July 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 1 August 1779, Washington
            to Sullivan; 4 August 1779, Washington to Sullivan. [According to Fitzpatrick,
            Washington, footnotes p. 106, volume XVI, the following letters were also enclosed in 15
            August 1779, Washington to JJ: 27 April 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 8 May 1779,
            Washington to Sullivan; 19 April 1779, Washington to Sullivan; 20 May 1779, Washington
            to Sullivan; 11 February 1779, Washington to Sullivan. However, they are not to be found
            among the enclosures in PCC: 169, vols. V and VI.]</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79088877">
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">UkWC-A</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Royal Archives, Windsor
                        Castle</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/image?key=columbia.jay.3574</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.03574_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general
                        conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>
