<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.07349</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, Sarah Livingston</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Gèrard, Conrad Alexandre, 1729-1790</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, Peter</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Livingston, Catharine</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Livingston, Susan</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Livingston, Susannah French</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Livingston, William, 1723-1790</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, ante 1765 and 1780 January 1 - 1781 March 14</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>21</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation"/>
   <mods:abstract>John Jay's School Copybook (ante 1765) and Sarah Jay's Letterbook, 1
            January 1780-14 March 1781. Paperbound copybook opening with eight leaves inscribed by
            John Jay, probably ante 1765, containing conjugations of French verbs and declensions of
            French nouns. The next twenty-seven pages contain Sarah Jay's drafts of letters to sent
            to friends and family , 1 January 1780-14 March 1781. The next four pages contain Mrs.
            Jay's transcriptions Lord Orrery's verses in memory of his wife; arithmetic notations
            inside the back cover. Sarah Jay's letters are: (1) To William Livingston, ca. 9 January
            1780 . Had intended to write from Martinique. Describes mishaps of the Confederacy and
            their eventual transfer to the Aurora. Description of St. Pierre and Martinique.
            Agriculture. Raising of cotton and cabbage. Her father would have enjoyed the West
            Indian fish. Bees introduced to the island only a year ago, and there are now 46 swarms.
            (2) To Peter Jay, ,[ 9] January 1780; Their difficult voyage and landing in Martinique.
            Visit from William Bingham. Viscount Damas reviews his regiment in the Jay's honor. For
            "brother Peter" (John Jay's blind older brother), describes the sugar cane mills of the
            island in great detail. Reports that Peter Jay Munro is "quite a favorite among the
            Officers of the frigate." (3) To Susannah French Livingston. 13 May 1780. Arrival in
            Madrid. Is pleased with city, but her ignorance of the language makes it difficult for
            her to make acquaintances. Chief amusement is riding. John Jay is at Aranjuez, where the
            court now resides. Describes beautiful road from Madrid to Aranjuez; watered by canals.
            Drought in Spain has hurt farming. King more fond of his country palaces than Madrid,
            which is "inconvenient and expensive to the foreign ambassadors and Ministers."
            Describes their rented house with its fountain in courtyard. Apologies for not having
            sent items her mother and sisters ordered. Europeans regard American highly. Sends
            recipe for scurvy remedy. Asks about Peter Augustus Jay and wonders if he still
            resembles his father;. Asks for news of the boy. Glad that he can spend this time with
            his grandparents, "imbibing with his earliest acquirements that probity &amp; generosity
            that reigns throughout the family." (4) To Catharine Livingston. 14 May 1780. Joy at
            receiving Kitty's letter. Mrs. Price's death. Complains that Kitty writes nothing of
            Mary White Morris. Madrid's walks and public gardens. Court at Aranjuez; will move again
            next month. Sends regards to John Penn. Reflects on his friendship. Has tried to ship
            silk handkerchiefs, but found none of good quality. Gauze handkerchiefs, silk stockings,
            sewing silk and goods for Peter Augustus's clothes sent instead. "There is not any thing
            here of the first quality -- every thing is slight, tawdry &amp; High priced." (5) To
            Susannah French Livingston. 18 August 1780. Fragment, being only the first page of a
            draft letter with this date, finally sent with the date of 28 August (see document
            7352). A touching letter informing her mother of the conditions surrounding the death of
            her new born baby girl.. (6) To Judith Livingston Watkins, 18 August 1780. Congratulates
            her sister on her marriage. Quotes the Count of Orrery on marriage (7) To Mary White
            Morris, [1 September 1780]. Does not believe their friendship has been diminished by
            absence. Thanks Mr. and Mrs. Morris for their kindness to her sister, Kitty. Still
            grieves for the loss of her daughter. Sympathizes with Gouverneur Morris for the "cruel
            accident" which has befallen him. Sends remembrances to friends in Philadelphia. Jay due
            to return from St. Ildefonso; she will write then as his company will surely revive her
            spirits. (8) To Conrad Gerard, 14 March 1781. Thanks him for the Du Simitiere print (9)
            To William Livingston, 14 March 1781. Regrets that letter she wrote him in January 1780
            was apparently lost. Apologizes and explains at length for not having written later.
            Sorrow at death of daughter Susan. Condolences to Uncle and Aunt Livingston on their
            sons' death. Enjoys happiness and perfect health now. Season of year lovely in Madrid.
            King's improvements to city and adjacent country by walks, fountains, roads, trees. King
            has four country seats which he visits in turn and prefers to Madrid because of fondness
            for hunting. Aranjuez his favorite. Sarah will visit there in May but cannot afford a
            long trip. Describes items on exhibition in king's armory. (10) To Peter Jay. ca. 14
            March 1781, entered following her letter of this date to her own father. Sends on news
            of Peter Augustus that she has received from her family in New Jersey. Asks after
            Frederick, Margaret, Peter and Nancy Jay. Sends this message for her blind
            brother-in-law: "Tell Peter that his friend Townsend was extremely mistaken about the
            Coffee, it grows as Depeyster said inclos'd in red berries Resembling cherries upon
            trees that have leaves very like peach leaves."</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79088877">
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">UkWC-A</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Royal Archives, Windsor
                        Castle</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/image?key=columbia.jay.7349</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.07349_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general
                        conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>
