<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.04402</mods:identifier>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1782 November 30</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>9</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1782 November 30</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17821130</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>Provisional articles of peace, agreed upon between Richard Oswald of Great
            Britain and John Adams, Benjamin Franklin, John Jay and Henry Laurens of the United
            States. Treaty not finished until Great Britain makes peace with France. Article 1.
            Great Britain acknowledges sovereignty and independence of named states and relinquishes
            all claim to governmental and territorial rights. Article 2. Exact boundaries described.
            Article 3. Fishing rights secured for United States in Newfoundland, Gulf of St.
            Lawrence and Atlantic Ocean and in unsettled areas of Nova Scotia. Article 4. Creditors
            of both sides to receive payments of lawful debts. Article 5. Congress to recommend to
            state legislatures the restitution of confiscated property of British subjects and those
            in British-controlled territory who had not fought against the United States, All others
            allowed to go to any state for one year in order to obtain restitution of property.
            Congress to recommend to the states the restitution of such property and the
            reimbursement of those who had since bought the confiscated property. Article 6. No
            future confiscations or prosecutions against people because of their role in the present
            war. Those confined on those charges to be set free immediately upon ratification.
            Article 7. Hostilities between both sides to cease immediately; prisoners set free and
            British troops and ships to withdraw without "any destruction or carrying away [of] any
            Negroes or other property of the American inhabitants." All documents, records, deeds
            and papers of American citizens to be returned to their proper owner. Article 8.
            Navigation of the Mississippi River to remain open to United States and Great Britain.
            Article 9. Any territory conquered by either side before the peace treaty reaches
            America will be restored without need of compensation. Separate article. Redrawing of
            one boundary if Great Britain should regain control of West Florida.</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject>
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">UkWC-A</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Royal Archives, Windsor
                        Castle</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/image?key=columbia.jay.4402</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.04402_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general
                        conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>