<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.08531</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Grenville, Lord</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1794 August 30</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>3</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1794 August 30</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17940830</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>Same as covering letter for enclosures, DNA: 4314 Encloses two "projects",
            one for a general treaty, one for a commercial treaty. Asks John Jay to discuss them
            with them once he has studied them carefully. Does not consider these "projects" final
            by any means, but knew Jay would want to have them as soon as possible and so did not
            enlarge upon certain points and may have omitted some points he should have made. Has
            used suggestions of Jay's project of 6 August. Enclosures: 1) General treaty Evacuation
            of forts by 1 June 1796. Freedom of passage on waterways adjacent to Great Lakes.
            Detailed description of Commission to determine United States boundaries. Suggestions
            for correction of United States northern boundary west of Lakes. Selection and powers of
            Commissioners to determine compensation due British creditors and American who have
            suffered illegal condemnation of ships and to British subjects who have suffered losses
            by privateers operating within United States waters or from United States ports. Neutral
            commerce with European enemies of one or the other nations--Britain and United States to
            regard each other's shipping as having rights of most favored neutral nations. If one
            nation should remain neutral when other at war, not to allow operation of privateers
            from her ports. Citizens of neither nation to be allowed to act as privateers, under
            letters of marque from the enemy of other nation, against the other's shipping. Neither
            nation to harbor privateers preying upon other's vessels If two nations at war, 9 months
            allowed to citizens to return to homelands and no confiscation of funds during
            hostilities. Property rights of American and British nationals in each other's lands to
            be respected. 2) Commercial treaty Reciprocal freedom of ports. Appointment of consuls."
            Most favored nation" treatment of each other's commercial shipping. No further
            restrictions on import or export of goods to be laid. West Indian shipping: limits on
            size of American ships in trade; no duties other than those paid by British vessels.
            Provisions on West Indian shipping to remain in force until two years after conclusion
            of present war with France. Other articles to remain in force for twelve years after
            execution of treaty. Four months' notice necessary for suspension of any
            provision.</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject>
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">UkWC-A</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Royal Archives, Windsor
                        Castle</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/image?key=columbia.jay.8531</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.08531_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general
                        conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>