<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.07721</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Carmichael, William, -1795</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1784 April 24</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>9</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1784 April 24</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17840424</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>A long letter involving the private account between Jay and Carmichael
            dealing with the sale of furniture Jay left in Madrid and the payment of wages by
            Carmichael to the wife of a servant in Jay's employ. Jay inquires why Carmichael failed
            to enumerate the exact sum owed to Jay by Carmichael for "wines, etc." and the sum owed
            Carmichael by Jay for "sundry expenses attending sales." Heal so asks why there are such
            discrepancies between the price at which the furniture was appraised and the sum they
            actually brought. Lastly, Jay notes that there is no mention in Carmichael's account of
            the return of part of the furniture to the original dealer, who promised to accept it
            and return 3/4 of the original price if it were returned within three years. He would
            like an explicit answer to each of these three points. He repeats his instructions to
            Carmichael of 28 Jan. 1784, when he asked Carmichael to sell all his remaining effects
            before leaving Madrid at whatever price they would fetch so that he could once and for
            all settle all his accounts before leaving for America. The second half of the letter
            deals with Carmichael's account of the money Carmichael says he paid to a servant's
            wife. Jay had taken a certain Manuel with him to Paris and had instructed Carmichael to
            pay to Manuel's wife a part of her husband's wages, giving Jay an account of the sums he
            advanced so that Jay could deduct them from Manuel's salary. Carmichael never gave Jay
            any account of the sums he gave Manuel's wife, nor did he answer Manuel's letter asking
            for this information. Consequently Jay was forced to pay Manuel his total wages at the
            end of his service, and now he discovers that Carmichael says he gave to Manuel's wife a
            total sum larger than the whole of Manuel's wages. Furthermore, Jay quotes from the
            original and adds a translation of a letter from Manuel's wife to her husband dated 16
            Oct. 1782 in which she stated that Carmichael told her he had instructions not to give
            her any of Manuel's wages and that anything he had given her or gave her in the future
            was a favor. In this letter Manuel's wife also wrote that Carmichael was "scandalized"
            at the treatment Manuel received at the hands of Mrs. Jay and that he believed Mr. Jay
            would set it right. It does not appear necessary, Jay concludes, to make any remarks
            upon this matter.</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79088877">
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">NNC-RB</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Columbia University, Butler Library, Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Division</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/image?key=columbia.jay.7721</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.07721_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general
                        conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>