<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <mods:identifier type="local">columbia.jay.11969</mods:identifier>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">aut</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">author</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:name>
      <mods:namePart>Livingston, Robert R.</mods:namePart>
      <mods:role>
         <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="code">rcp</mods:roleTerm>
         <mods:roleTerm type="text">addressee</mods:roleTerm>
      </mods:role>
   </mods:name>
   <mods:titleInfo supplied="yes">
      <mods:title>Document, 1783 July 19</mods:title>
   </mods:titleInfo>
   <mods:physicalDescription>
      <mods:extent>8 pages</mods:extent>
      <mods:form authority="gmgpc">correspondence</mods:form>
      <mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
   </mods:physicalDescription>
   <mods:originInfo eventType="creation">
      <mods:dateCreated>1783 July 19</mods:dateCreated>
      <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">17830719</mods:dateCreated>
   </mods:originInfo>
   <mods:abstract>Postpones full justification for signing provisional articles but sends
            own private remarks. Doubts of Livingston enumerated: negotiators overly distrustful and
            the agreement signed without prior knowledge of French court. Reminder that the American
            commissioners insisted on four things from the British a priori that the French minister
            believed premature or excessive: treatment of America as independent nation, agreement
            to boundaries claimed by the United States, fishing rights, and no definite
            reinstatement of Tories. Evident that the French did not have American best interest in
            mind, whatever the ministerÆs motives were. Reason for not communicating articles to
            French before signing: Lord Shelbourne feared would have to resign if no speedy
            conclusion to war and saw negotiations as furthering this end, thus the British made
            concessions would not have otherwise made. Also, the King agreed to ratify only what Mr.
            Oswald should sign and seal, not a verbal agreement. French, if given articles, would
            have postponed signing of agreement until French, Spanish and British treaty could be
            signed as well. Delay giving opening for British to consider themselves not bound by
            present articles and allowing France to pressure British to not concede to our demands.
            Too risky to not act as they did. Because signed in secret, avoided the necessity of
            offending the French in refusing to postpone signing. Although admits diverged from
            resolution of Congress, believes wording of resolution called for France to assist the
            United States in its aims, not discourage their completion. Confidence between allies
            already marred by French ministerÆs lack of support for articles. French minister did
            not show the Americans his articles, so hardly surprising the Americans did the same.
            Considers LivingstonÆs resignation due to his desire for happiness over wishes for the
            public good. Still many difficulties ahead, despite end of war and need for "advise and
            wisdom of our best men to manage". Has learned family needs nothing at present, but
            Livingston should talk to his brother Peter to learn of any needs unmet. Hopes to return
            next spring. Question of Tories. Opinion in Europe that ought to be generous towards
            them but they do not know "what inhuman barbarian wretches the greater part of them have
            been". Wants the United States to have consistent, just law in dealing with them. Ought
            to pardon all except the faithless and the cruel. Congratulations on children; would be
            godfather to second one. Little girl well and expecting new birth next month. Increase
            in family compared to situation of ancestors exiled from this country. Health
            improved.</mods:abstract>
   <mods:note>The entire content of the original has been digitized.</mods:note>
   <mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh"
                 valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139">
      <mods:topic>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</mods:topic>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:subject authority="lcsh"
                 valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79088877">
      <mods:name authority="naf">
         <mods:namePart>Jay, John, 1745-1829</mods:namePart>
      </mods:name>
   </mods:subject>
   <mods:location>
      <mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="code">PPIn</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:physicalLocation type="text">Independence National Historical Park</mods:physicalLocation>
      <mods:url usage="primary display" access="object in context">http://wwwapp.cc.columbia.edu/ldpd/jay/item?mode=item&amp;key=columbia.jay.11969</mods:url>
   </mods:location>
   <mods:relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
      <mods:titleInfo>
         <mods:nonSort>The</mods:nonSort>
         <mods:title>Papers of John Jay</mods:title>
      </mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:originInfo eventType="publication">
         <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>New York, NY</mods:placeTerm>
         </mods:place>
         <mods:publisher>Columbia University Libraries</mods:publisher>
      </mods:originInfo>
      <mods:location>
         <mods:url>http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/cul/resolve?AVE8231</mods:url>
      </mods:location>
   </mods:relatedItem>
   <mods:accessCondition type="use and reproduction">For rights relating to this resource, visit http://www.columbia.edu/cu/lweb/digital/jay/copyright.html</mods:accessCondition>
   <mods:recordInfo>
      <mods:languageOfCataloging>
         <mods:languageTerm>eng</mods:languageTerm>
      </mods:languageOfCataloging>
      <mods:recordIdentifier>columbia.jay.11969_mods.xml</mods:recordIdentifier>
      <mods:recordContentSource authority="marcorg">NNC</mods:recordContentSource>
      <mods:recordOrigin>Derived from John Jay Papers metadata and edited in general conformance to MODS Guideline (Version 3).</mods:recordOrigin>
   </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>
